### Tahreen Zeba

98 Plymouth Drive -Iselin, New Jersey, 08830

Phone: (551) 247-8967, Email: tahreenzebai@gmail.com

Github: <a href="https://github.com/zeba-tahreen">https://github.com/zeba-tahreen</a>,

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tahreen-zeba-4b8780186">https://www.linkedin.com/in/tahreen-zeba-4b8780186</a>,

Portfolio: <a href="https://zeba-tahreen.github.io">https://zeba-tahreen.github.io</a>

## **Summary**

Web Developer specializing in front end development. Experienced with all stages of full MERN stack development with a passion for creating flexible and efficient code, also background in fashion education has helped me to develop prominent skills to creatively capture the attention of the community. I have worked both individually and as a group, organizing and achieving goals. Persisted through challenges with optimism to accomplish learning through Rutgers Coding Bootcamp, ready and ambitious to grow my career in web development.

## **Technical Skills**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, JSON, APIs, Git/Github, Visual Studio Code (VSC), Bootstrap, Node.js, MongoDB, Postman, Express, React.js, Redux, Heroku.

#### Soft Skills

- Creative and Innovative Designs
- Search Engine Optimization
- Service-Focused
- Complex Problem Solver
- Work Ethic

- Strong Decision Maker
- Growth Mindset
- Excellent Communicator
- Highly Flexible
- Team Player

# **Projects**

Client

**Global Tuch** - *IT Infrastructure Solutions* 

Github: Private-Code

Live: http://www.globaltuch.com/

- Global Tuch Solutions is a local firm partnered with global brands to push out IT security and IT solutions using advanced cutting edge technology to increase client's productivity.
- This is a React Project.

 Tools used are React-Bootstrap for Styling, Visual Studio Code as Code Editor and Deployed on Heroku Cloud Application Platform.

Personal

CookBook - Belly Rules the Mind

Github: https://github.com/zeba-tahreen/CookBook

Live: \*\*\*\*\*\* Link \*\*\*\*\*\*\*\*\*\*

- CookBook is an open source app for every person to look for easy quick recipes created by common people who are chefs by themself. This app is to inspire and encourage people to experiment their cooking skills to eat homemade food everyday.
- Languages used are MongoDB, Express, React, Redux and Node.js.
- Tools used are Passport Js for registration and login authentication, Reactstrap, Styled Components with Bootstrap as NPM Packages for Styling, Visual Studio Code as Code Editor and Deployed on Heroku Cloud Application Platform.

Group

**Common Grounds** - *Let's Meet* 

Github: <a href="https://github.com/krenaldi/Common-Grounds">https://github.com/krenaldi/Common-Grounds</a></a>
Live: <a href="https://krenaldi.github.io/Common-Grounds">https://krenaldi.github.io/Common-Grounds</a>

- Common Grounds was the first group project of our academic batch. Our idea was to find an easy and fun way to schedule a public get-together, so that we can meet our friends or colleagues without usual hassle.
- Languages used are MongoDB, Express, React, JavaScript, AJAX.
- Tools used are Passport Js and Bcrypt Js for registration and login authentication, Material UI with CSS and SASS for Styling, Visual Studio Code as Code Editor and Deployed on Heroku Cloud Application Platform.

## **Experience**

September 2020 - PRESENT

#### Amazon Fulfillment Center (LGA9), Edison- New Jersey- Ambassador

- In charge of conducting orientation and training with new hires on start date.
- Doing follow up on all the employees making sure they are meeting Amazon scan rates and goals.
- Ensuring all Amazon safety standards are met and employees comply with the safety standards.
- Quick identify the problem and take appropriate actions to correct the problem.
- Team up with the other coaches to make sure the packing is done 100% effectively.
- Established and adjusted work procedures to meet production schedules.

#### Amazon Fulfillment Center (LGA9), Edison- New Jersey- Associate

- Outbound singles packing of customers packages.
- Worked in a fast paced environment with safety and quality.
- Worked in Vendor Returns to meet the business needs in packing the LTL, Donations, Recycles, Liquidations, Pallet Wrapping and staging of pallets.
- Worked in line straightening and jam clearance to keep up the work flow.
- Flexible, works well under pressure.

March 2018 - March 2020

## Amazon Fulfillment Center (EWR6), Avenel - New Jersey- Associate

- Outbound processing of Pick, Slam and Ship Dock of customer packages.
- Highest rate in Slam, best slammer of the shift.
- Worked in teams to meet end of shift deadlines.
- Worked in a very fast paced environment with maintaining the quality standards.
- Duties included but not limited to picking, packing(Slam), audit, sorting, pallet wrapping and staging of pallets.
- Problem solving duties involving damaged products or missing packages and re-picking for the current CPT and departing the truck on time with 100% accuracy.
- Also worked in Inbound stowing for business requirements.

June 2016 - March 2018

#### Kanha Collection, Jersey City - New Jersey- Store Manager

- Established and optimized schedules to keep coverage and service in line with forecasted demands.
- Built a talented and valuable team of departmental employees through outstanding mentoring, coaching and teaching skills.
- Multiplied earnings through sales goal achievement, customer service improvements and commitment to team objectives.
- Supported professional development of team members and supervisors at all levels to place knowledgeable candidates in leadership roles.
- Trained team members in successful strategies to meet operational and sales targets.
- Oversaw employee performance, corrected problems and increased efficiency to maintain productivity targets
- Offering hands-on assistance to customers, assessing needs and maintaining current knowledge of consumer preferences.
- Managed all aspects of store operations, including organization, maintenance and purchasing functions.
- Strengthened merchandising and promotional strategies to drive customer engagement and boost sales.

- Kept orderly and accurate accounting records by monitoring sales documentation.
- Managed weekly inventory transactions by creating templates to ensure optimal food and beverage stock for employees.

## Education

Year: 2019

Rutgers University, Somerset- Full Stack MERN Developer

Year: 2015 - 2016

Fashion Institute of Technology, New York - AAS Degree Program

Year: 2012 - 2014

**Lakhotia Institute of Design, India** – *Diploma in Fashion Design* – *Apparel* 

Year: 2007 - 2010

St. George's Degree College For Women, India- Bachelor of Commerce

Year: 2005 - 2007

**Shadan Women's College, India** - Associate Degree - Commerce

Year: 2005

St. George's Girls Grammar School, India- High School - Commerce (ICSE)

Language's Speak

English, Hindi and Urdu